{"tossups": [{"question": "A homeless girl in this novel nicknamed Vagabondella was captured and put towork on a state farm. The protagonist of this novel meets a girlfriend at a showing ofthe film Court of Honor. Another character in this novel uses the analogy of the danceof seven veils to describe the layers of (+) Moravian folk music. The protagonist hasan affair in his friend Kostka's apartment. In this novel's last section, which centers on the Ride of the Kings ritual, (*) Helena Zemanek attempts suicide and the protagonist plays with Jaroslav in a cimbalom band. The protagonist dates Lucie Sebetka while working in a mining camp after sending a postcard to his girlfriend Marketa stating \"Optimism is the opium of the people!\" For ten points, name this novel about the political outcast Ludvik Jahn written by Milan Kundera.", "answer": "The Joke (or Z\u02c7ert )", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Joke</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Joke", "Joke"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or Z\u02c7ert"}, {"question": "In one story by this writer, a tombstone-shaped sign saying \"Effects of MacGorkle's whiskey, - kills at forty rods\" is left next to a passed-out drunk. In that work, the school teacher Miss Mary receives azaleas and favors after rescuing that man, Sandy, and adopts his son, Tommy. In another story by this writer, a man nicknamed (+) \"The Innocent\" lost forty dollars to a gambler, who gave it all back and warned him never to gamble again. Another character in that story starved herself to give her rations to (*) Piney, while the protagonist announced his suicide with a deuce of clubs pinned by knife to a tree. This author of The Idyl of Red Gulch wrote of Mother Shipton and John Oakhurst dying when their camp was snowed in after being exiled from the title town. For the points, name this author of The Outcasts of Poker Flat.", "answer": "Bret Harte", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Bret <b><u>Harte</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Bret Harte", "Harte"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this drama, the protagonist exclaims \"Out, out, hy\u00c3\u00a6na\" when approached byhis wife and refuses her offers of care, saying \"No, no, of my condition take no care/It fits not; thou and I long since are twain\". The protagonist of this drama challengesa giant three times to a fight, but each time is denied by that man, (+) Harapha ofGath. The protagonist refuses to go with the Public Officer to perform at a feast, but the Chorus convinces him to go after all. The protagonist's father (*) Manoa visits to negotiate a ransom while his son is performing at a feast for Dagon the sea-idol. The protagonist finds \"Himself in bonds under Philistian yoke\" and laments being \"Eyeless in Gaza\". For ten points, name this closet drama about a fallen strongman, the husband of Dalila, written by John Milton.", "answer": "Samson Agonistes", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Samson Agonistes</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Samson Agonistes", "Samson Agonistes"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this novel, the most recent presidential election saw Hubert Hoag lose ina landslide to Winston Noble. One character in this novel complains that all artis abstract, although in the past paintings had shown people. The protagonist'sreminiscing about playing in the sand with his cousin in interrupted by a commercialfor (+) Denham's Dentafrice. One character, who introduces herself as seventeen andcrazy, is afraid of children her own age because sixteen of her friends died in a year from shootings and car wrecks. The neighbor of (*) Clarisse McClellan goes on to meet with Faber, who flees to St. Louis after Captain Beatty discovers him. For ten points, name this novel in which a Mechanical Hound pursues the fireman Guy Montag, written by Ray Bradbury.", "answer": "Fahrenheit 451                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                 ", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Fahrenheit 451</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Fahrenheit 451", "Fahrenheit 451"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The protagonist of this novel is attacked by a gang of boys after he scored poorlyon a grip tester at the Gun Corner Arcade. That protagonist dreams of writing atravel chronicle called Sky Over Africa, and reads The Sun Also Rises to his (+)class before collapsing to vomit. One character in this novel explains pluralistic universes before informing the protagonist that he raped her. That character helps the protagonist find an (*) abortion doctor to murder his newborn son, but he leaves her and saves his baby instead. The protagonist visits the mistress Himiko in, for ten points, which novel in which Bird struggles to accept his \"abnormal\" son written by Kenzaburo Oe?", "answer": "A Personal Matter (or Kojinteki na taiken)", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "A <b><u>Personal Matter</u></b>", "acceptable": ["A Personal Matter", "Personal Matter"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or Kojinteki na taiken"}, {"question": "In this novel, the protagonist sees one hawk attacking another, causing a visionof his oasis coming under siege. That protagonist of this novel was later releasedfrom a militant camp after turning himself into the wind. The protagonist tells a(+) gypsy palm reader about his recurring dream of hidden treasure at the Egyptian pyramids before meeting Melchizedek, the King of Salem, who gives him black and white stones for reading omens called (*) Urim and Thummim. The protagonist works for a crystal merchant in Tangier after selling his flock in Andalusia and before joining a caravan to cross the Sahara. For ten points, name this novel in which the title character teaches Santiago how to fulfill his Personal Legend written by Paulo Coelho.", "answer": "The Alchemist", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Alchemist</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Alchemist", "Alchemist"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This author wrote a novel in which a rehab facility in Peril Strait serves as afront for raising red heifers. In that novel, Mendel Shpilman was considered to bethe Tzaddik Ha-Dor, and the shooting of Emanuel Lasker at the Hotel Zamenhofis investigated before the (+) Federal District of Sitka reverts to Alaska. In anothernovel by this author, a character beats up Carl Ebling after breaking into the office of the Aryan American League. Earlier, that character had escaped from (*) Prague with the help of magician Bernard Kornblum. This author of The Yiddish Policemen's Union wrote of Sammy and Joe creating The Escapist for Empire Comics. For ten points, name this author of The Amazing Adventures of Kavalier &amp; Clay.", "answer": "Michael Chabon                                                                                                                                                                                                             ", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Michael <b><u>Chabon</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Michael Chabon", "Chabon"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This author ends a short poem \"Lifting my head/ I watch the bright moon,/Lowering my head/ I dream that I'm home\". In another work, this poet toasts themoon because it and his shadow give him two companions. This author of (+) QuietNight Thoughts notes that \"a cup of wine levels life and death\" and says that he would never tell his secrets to a sober person. The narrator of another of his poems speaks of the loud sound of (*) monkeys after a five month absence and promises to come meet her addressee \"as far as Cho-fu-sa\". That narrator, Rihaku, mentions her hair being cut straight across her forehead when her future husband passes on bamboo stilts and laments his departure at 16 for the Yangtze. For ten points, name this Tang-era poet of Drinking Alone by Moonlight and The River Merchant's Wife.", "answer": "Li Bai (or Li Po)", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Li <b><u>Bai</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Li Bai", "Bai"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or Li Po"}, {"question": "The protagonist of this novel plays a game of checkers with whiskey bottle pieces,and he met his secretary when she spilled Coke on a policeman at the TropicanaClub. A dog dies from drinking the protagonist's poisoned whiskey when he speaks ata luncheon of the (+) European Traders Association. The protagonist communicateswith his boss Hawthorne using Lamb's Tales From Shakespeare as a book code. Police Captain Segura courts the protagonist's daughter (*) Milly but does not investigate the murder of his friend Dr. Hasselbacher. Drawings of the Atomic Pile are passed off as constructions in Oriente, causing the protagonist and his partner Beatrice Severn to be fired by their bosses in London. For ten points, name this novel about Joe Wormold, a vacuum-cleaner-salesman-turned- spy written by Graham Greene.", "answer": "Our Man in Havana", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Our Man in Havana</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Our Man in Havana", "Our Man in Havana"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The narrator of one story by this author researches the question \"Whence does theearth procure this food?\" and questions the sense of soaring dogs. That protagonistclaimed to lose his childhood after finding seven musical dogs walking on their hindlegs. The protagonist of another short story by this author earned the nickname (+)Red Peter after being shot by a hunting expedition and is kept in a three-sided cage, where he learns to spit, smoke, and drink by mimicking sailors despite being an (*) ape. This author of Investigations of a Dog and A Report to an Academy wrote a novella in which the narrator's sister Grete feeds him milk while he hides under the sofa and his father kills him with an apple after he awakens as a bug. For ten points, identify this man who wrote of Gregor Samsa in The Metamorphosis.", "answer": "Franz Kafka", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Franz <b><u>Kafka</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Franz Kafka", "Kafka"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One man in this book openly defies the instructions of a letter signed by \"D.R.ANTHONY AND 1,000 OTHERS\". Another man in this book justifies a decisionusing the anecdote of a Confederate Captain who overruled his orders to enterSavannah harbor following the advice of his lookout. In the preface, this book's authorcredits his (+) \"research associate, Theodore C. Sorensen\". Each of this book's fourparts opens with an introduction titled \"The Time and The Place\". One chapter talks of George Norris touring Nebraska to explain his (*) filibuster of the Armed Ships Bill, and another discusses Edmund Ross's \"not guilty\" vote in the Johnson impeachment. Other chapters follow Robert Taft, Thomas Hart Benton, and Daniel Webster. For ten points, name this collection of eight biographical sketches of Senators written by John F. Kennedy.", "answer": "Profiles in Courage", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Profiles in Courage</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Profiles in Courage", "Profiles in Courage"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This playwright wrote of Sammy Goldenbaum committing suicide in OklahomaCity after attending a party with Reenie in a work ending with Rubin Flood returningto his wife Cora. In another work of this writer, (+) Turk poses with a javelin forMarie, who is engaged to Bruce from Cincinnati, and an alcoholic chiropractor falls off the wagon. This author of (*) The Dark at the Top of the Stairs and creator of Doc Delaney wrote a play in which Rosemary begs Howard to marry her and a fraternity brother of Alan Seymour works odd jobs for Helen Potts. Later, Madge skips the title event to have sex with Hal, who is run out of town and hops a train to Tulsa. For ten points, name this playwright of Come Back, Little Sheba and Picnic.", "answer": "William Inge", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>William Inge</u></b>", "acceptable": ["William Inge", "William Inge"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one poem, this author wrote of the \"stale\" \"fret and tumult\" of ordinarylife, concluding that \"men never can be still/ But in their graves\". In another work,he decided that if he lived to old age to \"Let them smile, as I do now/ At the oldforsaken bough/ Where I now cling\". This poet of (+) Daily Trials by a SensitiveMan and The Last Leaf wrote of hearing a \"clearer note...Then ever Triton blew from wreathed horn\" urging him to (*) \"Shut thee from heaven with a dome more vast\". He advocated that it was better to \"give her to the god of storms\", letting \"her shattered bulk\" and \"every threadbare sail\" sink in one work and lamented a \"Wrecked...ship of pearls\" that taught him to \"Build thee more stately mansions\". For ten points, name this Fireside poet of Old Ironsides and The Chambered Nautilus.", "answer": "Oliver Wendell Holmes, Sr.", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Oliver Wendell Holmes, Sr.</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Oliver Wendell Holmes, Sr.", "Oliver Wendell Holmes, Sr."], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this novella, elite students are taught at the University of Wentbridge. In onesociety in this novella, all births are of triplets with two girls and one boy in orderto maintain gender balance. The character of Chromatistes starts the (+) ColourRevolt, which is opposed by women and priests. Rain always falls from the north, and fog aids characters in Sight Recognition, an alternative to feeling. The narrator is visited by a stranger who removes an accounting tablet from a locked (*) cupboard, and the protagonist is later imprisoned for espousing the motto \"Upward, not Northward!\". Women in this novella are line segments and men are polygons. For ten points, name this novella by Edwin Abbott, written under the pseudonym A Square, that explores two-dimensional life.", "answer": "Flatland: A Romance of Many Dimensions", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Flatland: A Romance of Many Dimensions</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Flatland: A Romance of Many Dimensions", "Flatland: A Romance of Many Dimensions"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Members of this profession attended the Konakai s \u0301eance, at which they werewarned about their promiscuity. A poem by W. H. Auden considers the \"phallictriumph\" of this profession. This profession was opposed by Integral, led by the (+)Chief Designer. The towns of Perth and Rockingham in western Australia left their lights on at midnight to recognize one holder of this job. One of them was reprimanded by his boss, James E. Webb, for not allowing Vice President (*) Lyndon Johnson into his house. Pete Conrad was not chosen as one of the Original Seven in this field, but was included in the Next Nine after a successful career as a Navy test pilot. For ten points, name this occupation chronicled by Tom Wolfe in The Right Stuff, which told of Project Mercury members Alan Shepard and John Glenn.", "answer": "astronaut (prompt on \"pilot\" or \"fighter pilot\")", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>astronaut</u></b>", "acceptable": ["astronaut", "astronaut"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "prompt on \"pilot\" or \"fighter pilot\""}, {"question": "In one of this man's plays, it is discovered that one character's tattoo of \"TheAvenger\" is actually just drawn in ink. In that play, Maurice tells of a murder victimfound with lilacs in her hair and Lefranc is accused of dishonesty in writing lettersto the girlfriend of Green Eyes. In another play by this author of (+) Deathwatch,two sisters vie for the milkman Mario and speculate on whether Monsieur, who is on trial, will face imprisonment on Devil's Island. (*) Madame narrowly avoids drinking tea laced with phenobarbital when she notices the phone off its hook. Claire and Solange take turns dressing as their boss and insulting each other for being of the \"putrid lot\" of servants. For ten points, name this French playwright of The Maids.", "answer": "Jean Genet", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Jean Genet</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Jean Genet", "Jean Genet"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one story by this author, Lewis Spiers leaves a poem criticizing creationistswhen he euthanizes himself for relief from ALS. In another work, the narrator writes astory about her great aunt dying in a lamp explosion, which gets her ex-communicatedby her cousin Alfrida. In addition to (+) Comfort, this author wrote about thephilanderous Grant having an affair with Marian so that her husband can keep his wife company in a nursing home. In another story, (*) Sabitha fakes love letters from Ken Boudreau which convince Johanna to move to Gdynia, Saskatchewan to marry him. For ten points, name this author of Family Furnishings, The Bear Came Over the Mountain, and Hateship, Friendship, Courtship, Loveship, Marriage, a Canadian short story writer who won the 2013 Nobel Prize in Literature.", "answer": "Alice Ann Munro", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Alice Ann <b><u>Munro</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Alice Ann Munro", "Munro"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One character in this play recognizes her long-lost brother by a hair twirl.Another character in this play spent the previous day looking for chicken wire, butonly came back with a London newspaper. After his Rolls-Royce gets caught in the(+) snow, Mr. Paravicini enters unexpectedly. The radio reports the murder of Mrs. Maureen Lyon, who had been imprisoned in the Longridge Farm case. Sergeant Trotter of the Berkshire police enters on (*) skis. Mrs. Boyle is strangled and found by the proprietress Mollie Ralston, and the culprit is eventually revealed to be the pseudonymous Georgie. Trotter had been tipped off by a note with the address of Monkswell Manor and the music to Three Blind Mice. For ten points, name this murder mystery play by Agatha Christie.", "answer": "The Mousetrap", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Mousetrap</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Mousetrap", "Mousetrap"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One poem by this writer recounts the stories of Orpheus and Aphrodite beforedeclaring that the gods and goddesses are crying; that poem begins \"Even thebeautiful must die\". This author of (+) N \u0308anie           wrote a play in whichMelchtal and a council representing three territories agree to postpone a revolt until Christmas. In that play, John Parricida dresses as a monk to visit the title character, who had helped Baumgarten escape during a storm in (*) Ruodi's boat. This poet wrote \"Every man becomes a brother/ Where thy gentle wings abide\" in a work dedicated to the \"daughter of Elysium\". The protagonist of the aforementioned play is imprisoned by Gessler for refusing to salute a hat on a pole despite shooting an apple from his son's head. For ten points, name this writer of Ode to Joy and William Tell.", "answer": "Friedrich Schiller", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Friedrich <b><u>Schiller</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Friedrich Schiller", "Schiller"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This character has his servants carry in and remove a table of food to tantalizetwo guests before declaring \"I am Power.\" This character becomes distrustful whenhe hears the song of Eshu. In another appearance, this man warns his daughter'sbetrothed not to \"break her (+) virgin-knot\". This man, who was adapted into aslavemaster by Aime Cesaire, discovers a chess match before his daughter remarks \"How beauteous mankind is! O (*) brave new world\". He orders a performance by Iris, Ceres, and Juno before declaring that \"We are such stuff as dreams are made on\". This \"wronged Duke of Milan\" is the subject of a coup attempt by Stephano and Trinculo, for which he pardons Caliban before freeing Ariel. For ten points, name this man who is marooned with his daughter Miranda in Shakespeare's The Tempest.", "answer": "Prospero", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Prospero</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Prospero", "Prospero"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}